<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ohio Code Dreams</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ohio Code Dreams</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdowntitle:&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdowntitle:&#34;&gt;date: 2025-07-19T08:00:00+08:00&#xA;draft: false&#xA;I’m Jake Miller, a history major from a dead-end Ohio town off Route 23, where the factories rusted out and the Buckeyes are the only thing keeping us sane. I’ve got a master’s from Ohio State that’s collecting dust, $1,200 in Navient debt breathing down my neck, and a one-star Upwork review from a $50 gig I botched in Philly. Back in my hometown (pop. 3,000), I’m teaching myself Python, screwing up PTA workshops, and building dinky sites like Jerry’s Diner and Ohio Vitality 11. I’m no tech bro—just a guy stumbling through code, dodging Tammy’s gossip at Dollar General, and dreaming of something bigger than Taco Bell runs and Navient calls. Ohio Code Dreams is my story: the fails, the fights, and the faint hope I might actually make it as a coder. Stick around for the mess. #OhioCodeDreams&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdowntitle:&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdowntitle:&#34;&gt;date: 2025-07-18T10:42:00+08:00&#xA;draft: false&#xA;categories: [&amp;#34;Coding Fails&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Ohio Life&amp;#34;]&#xA;tags: [&amp;#34;Ohio&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;coding&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;career change&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Python&amp;#34;]&#xA;description: &amp;#34;Ohio history grad fights $40,000 debt and diner job to learn coding. Follow Jake’s raw journey to coder. #OhioCodeDreams&amp;#34;&#xA;featured_image: &amp;#34;/images/ohio-coding-diner.jpg&amp;#34;Starting from Zero: Ohio History Grad’s Coding JourneyFrom Ohio History Grad to Coding NewbieMay 2020. I clutched my history master’s over a glitchy Zoom stage, 26 and cocky, ready to lecture on the Tea Act or Shakespeare’s tobacco (harsh New World leaf). I pictured dusty archives or teaching Ohio undergrads about the Articles of Confederation. Wrong. The world needed ventilators, Zoom accounts, and coders for toilet paper apps.The pandemic hit like a Rust Belt factory closing—fast, brutal. My Philly Fishtown shoebox, split with Jake, my poli-sci roommate, cost $1,600 a month. My $40,000 Navient debt was a guillotine, the grace period ticking like a bomb. I slung burgers near Temple for $12 an hour, tips barely buying a Yuengling. COVID shut the diner to takeout-only. Customers vanished. My boss, Tony, a chain-smoking pancake flipper, got sick and didn’t make it. His wife, Maria, followed. I poured coffee for Uber drivers, dodging the news’ body count.Why Learn to Code in a Rust Belt Town?Every night, I came home reeking of fryer grease, sneakers caked in diner sludge, firing off resumes. Museums, libraries, nonprofits—nothing. The academic job market, a Hunger Games pre-COVID, was now a wasteland. I refreshed Gmail like a slot machine, craving even a rejection. Twitter screamed death tolls: “3,000 dead today.” “No end in sight.” On our Craigslist couch, nursing a warm Yuengling, I wondered how to pay rent in a collapsing world.History gives perspective—Spanish Flu, Black Death—but didn’t loosen Navient’s chokehold. I ran numbers: $450 monthly payments post-deferment, $800 rent, $200 groceries. I cleared $1,200 on a good month. My roommate Jake, with his useless poli-sci degree, split $5 pizzas, joking we’d eat Purina by 30. It wasn’t funny.The Coding LeapBy August, I was pulling double shifts, hands raw from sanitizing tables. Job boards listed software engineers, data analysts, nothing for historians. Museums were padlocked, universities slashed adjuncts. I applied to admin jobs, thinking research skills might translate. No luck. Navient’s letters grew meaner, demanding $300 a month on income-based repayment. I sobbed into a towel, broke.Then coding crept in—not a dream, a last resort. Jake’s cousin, a Seattle tech bro, bragged about his six-figure job. I hated his smug face but envied the paycheck. Tech was hiring. I googled “how to code,” found stories of teachers and bartenders turned coders. I signed up for a free bootcamp, expecting to fail. Variables, loops, syntax errors—it was hell. I’d curse, slam my laptop, but kept going. Navient wouldn’t wait.My First Gig (and Crash)By December, I could write a calculator that didn’t crash. Upwork became my Wild West. I found a gig: a $150 WordPress site for Brenda’s South Philly bakery. I faked confidence, got hired, then panicked. Her cheap hosting spat errors—Permission denied, Database connection failed. I wrestled Stack Overflow, CSS, SMTP plugins. The site was a mess: text spilled, images stretched. Brenda disputed, left a 1-star review: “Unreliable, site’s a mess. Avoid.” My hope died.I didn’t touch my laptop for weeks. The diner’s exhaust fan drowned my thoughts. But history taught me persistence. I took a better course, rebuilt Brenda’s site for practice. It wasn’t perfect, but it worked. Spring 2021, I landed a $15/hour WordPress assistant gig. It’s grunt work, fixing plugins, but it’s a crack in the door. I’m not a coder—not yet—but I’m not just a history grad either.Read more about my Ohio coding journey (/about) | Follow on X&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
